<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cookie on Spring Cloud</title>
    <link>https://www.springcloud.io/tags/cookie/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cookie on Spring Cloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 16:33:13 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.springcloud.io/tags/cookie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to set SameSite property for Cookie in SpringBoot application?</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-samesite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 16:33:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-samesite/</guid>
      <description>Starting with Chrome 51, a new SameSite attribute has been added to the browser cookie to prevent CSRF attacks and user tracking.
1. What is a CSRF attack? Cookies are often used to store a user&amp;rsquo;s identity information, and a malicious website can manage to forge an HTTP request with the correct cookie, which is a CSRF attack.
For example, a user logs into the bank&amp;rsquo;s website your-bank.com and a cookie is sent from the bank&amp;rsquo;s server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jwt should be present in the cookie</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-02/jwt-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 13:06:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-02/jwt-cookie/</guid>
      <description>I have been using JWT as authentication token for my projects in the last few years. I&amp;rsquo;ve always had a question: where exactly should the server-side issued JWT be stored? Only the browser scenario is discussed here, in which there are three options.
Cookies The server side can send the JWT token to the browser through a cookie, and the browser will automatically bring the JWT token in the cookie header when requesting the server-side interface, and the server side can verify the JWT token in the cookie header to achieve authentication.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
