<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>feign on Spring Cloud</title>
    <link>https://www.springcloud.io/tags/feign/</link>
    <description>Recent content in feign on Spring Cloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 16:22:41 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.springcloud.io/tags/feign/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Send a SOAP Object with Feign Client</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/feign-send-soap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 16:22:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/feign-send-soap/</guid>
      <description>1. Overview Feign abstracts the HTTP calls and makes them declarative. By doing so, Feign hides the lower-level details like HTTP connection management, hardcoded-URLs, and other boilerplate code. The significant advantage of using Feign clients is that HTTP calls are made easy and eliminate a lot of code. Typically, we use the Feign for REST APIs application/json media type. However, the Feign clients work well with other media types like text/xml , multipart requests, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solve the problem that RequestContextHolder.getRequestAttributes() returns null due to hystrix isolation policy</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-01/hystrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 17:11:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-01/hystrix/</guid>
      <description>What is the Hystrix Isolation Policy? Official documentation: https://github.com/Netflix/Hystrix/wiki/Configuration#executionisolationstrategy
Executing an isolation policy This property instructs HystrixCommand.run() which isolation policy to execute, being one of the following two options.
 THREAD - it is executed on a separate thread, and concurrent requests are limited by the number of threads in the thread pool SEMAPHORE - it is executed on the calling thread, and concurrent requests are limited by the amount of semaphore  Problem When the isolation policy is THREAD, there is no way to get the value in ThreadLocal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Spring Cloud Square</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2021-12/spring-cloud-square/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 16:26:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2021-12/spring-cloud-square/</guid>
      <description>Talking about Spring Cloud ecosystem, you must be familiar with Feign, as shown below, Feign can hide the underlying (okhttp, httpclient) Rest requests, disguised as a SpringMVC-like Controller. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to splice the url, splice the parameters and so on by yourself, everything is left to Feign. Using Feign to call the API is like calling a local method, avoiding the tedium of constantly parsing/wrapping json data when calling the target microservice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
