<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jackson on Spring Cloud</title>
    <link>https://www.springcloud.io/tags/jackson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jackson on Spring Cloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 14:45:37 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.springcloud.io/tags/jackson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jackson Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-07/jackson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 14:45:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-07/jackson/</guid>
      <description>JSON is not new to developers, as most of today&amp;rsquo;s web services, mobile applications, and even the Internet of Things use JSON as a data exchange format. Learning the tools for manipulating the JSON format is essential for developers. This article will describe how to use Jackson, an open source tool library, to perform common operations on JSON.
JSON Introduction What is JSON?JSON stands for &amp;ldquo;JavaScript Object Notation&amp;rdquo;, JSON is a text-based format that can be understood as a structured data that can contain key-value mapping, nested objects and arrays of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpringBoot With Gson</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-05/springboot-gson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 17:35:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-05/springboot-gson/</guid>
      <description>Spring Boot uses Jackson by default as the serialization/deserialization framework for Json. But for me, I prefer Google&amp;rsquo;s Gson, which is much more concise. This article will teach you how to use Gson instead of Jackson in your Spring Boot application.
maven Spring Boot itself provides support for Gson, so you can import the Gson module directly without declaring a version number. If you are not using Jackson elsewhere, then you can exclude it from your project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
