<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>release on Spring Cloud</title>
    <link>https://www.springcloud.io/categories/release/</link>
    <description>Recent content in release on Spring Cloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 19:19:10 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.springcloud.io/categories/release/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spring for GraphQL 1.0 RC1 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-for-graphql-1-0-rc1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 19:19:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-for-graphql-1-0-rc1-released/</guid>
      <description>On behalf of everyone involved, I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to announce the availability of the first and final release candidate of Spring for GraphQL 1.0. We&amp;rsquo;re finally going to release a 1.0 version on May 17, the reference version for Spring Boot 2.7.0. We&amp;rsquo;ve shipped a few noteworthy changes and one important new feature in this release.
 Note: The Spring for GraphqL Boot starter is up-to-date with the changes discussed in this post and Spring Boot 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Cloud Azure 4.0 is Now Generally Available</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-03/spring-cloud-azure-4-0-is-now-generally-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 16:30:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-03/spring-cloud-azure-4-0-is-now-generally-available/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: Hi, Spring fans! This is a guest post from Sean Li, our friend at Microsoft
 I am pleased to announce that Spring Cloud Azure 4.0 is now generally available. With this major release we aim to bring better security, leaner dependencies, support for production readiness and more. Version 4 represents a significant milestone in our product roadmap that we couldn&amp;rsquo;t have delivered without the collective wisdom of the Spring community and customer feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Authorization Server 0 2 3 Available Now</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-03/spring-authorization-server-0-2-3-available-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 08:45:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-03/spring-authorization-server-0-2-3-available-now/</guid>
      <description>⭐ New Features  Apply default settings for public client type #656 Decompose OAuth2ClientAuthenticationProvider #655 Optimize InMemoryOAuth2AuthorizationService #654 Federated Identity sample #641 Use OAuth2TokenGenerator for OAuth2AuthorizationCode #639 Add OAuth2TokenGenerator implementation for OAuth2RefreshToken #638 Allow Token Introspection to be customized #630 Introduce OAuth2TokenGenerator #628 Add Assert.notNull() for AuthenticationProvider additions #530 Support opaque access tokens #500 Allow Token Introspection to be customized #493 Seperate JWT Token generation #414 Add a login with Google Authorization Server Sample #106  🐞 Bug Fixes  Dynamic client registration should not generate client_secret for private_key_jwt #657 /.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Boot 2.6.5 Available Now</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-03/spring-boot-2-6-5-available-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 08:41:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-03/spring-boot-2-6-5-available-now/</guid>
      <description>⭐ New Features  Add EIGHTEEN to JavaVersion enum #30132  🐞 Bug Fixes  ConfigurationPropertyName#equals is not symmetric when adapt has removed trailing characters from an element #30392 Thymeleaf auto-configuration in a reactive application can fail due to duplicate templateEngine beans #30385 server.tomcat.keep-alive-timeout is not applied to HTTP/2 #30321 Setting spring.mustache.enabled to false has no effect #30256 bootWar is configured eagerly #30213 Actuator @ReadOperation on Flux cancels request after first element emitted #30161 Unnecessary allocations in Prometheus scraping endpoint #30125 No metrics are bound for R2DBC ConnectionPools that have been wrapped #30100 Condition evaluation report entry for a @ConditionalOnSingleCandidate that does not match due to multiple primary beans isn&amp;rsquo;t as clear as it could be #30098 Generated password are logged without an &amp;ldquo;unsuitable for production use&amp;rdquo; note #30070 Dependency management for Netty tcNative is incomplete leading to possible version conflicts #30038 Files in META-INF are not found when deploying a Gradle-built executable war to a servlet container #30036 Dependency management for Apache Kafka is incomplete #30031 spring-boot-configuration-processor fails compilation due to @DefaultValue with a long value and generates invalid metadata for byte and short properties with out-of-range default values #30022  📔 Documentation  Add Apache Kafka to the description of the Messaging section #30389 Default value of spring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Cloud 2021 0 0 Codename Jubilee Has Been Released</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2021-12/spring-cloud-2021-0-0-codename-jubilee-has-been-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:36:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2021-12/spring-cloud-2021-0-0-codename-jubilee-has-been-released/</guid>
      <description>On December 2, Spring Cloud officially released the first supported version of Spring Boot 2.6 with version number: 2021.0.0 and codename Jubilee.
Before we get into the details of the update, let&amp;rsquo;s mention the most important point: version 2021.0.0 corresponds to Spring Boot from 2.6.1, so don&amp;rsquo;t use version 2.6.0 if you&amp;rsquo;re upgrading.
Update Summary Spring Cloud Commons
Support for configuring for each load balance, this feature also applies to Gateway, Contract and Openfeign.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
