<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>spring-boot-actuator on Spring Cloud</title>
    <link>https://www.springcloud.io/tags/spring-boot-actuator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in spring-boot-actuator on Spring Cloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 15:47:28 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.springcloud.io/tags/spring-boot-actuator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exposing a Helpful Info Endpoint with Spring Boot Actuator</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-03/spring-boot-info-endpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 15:47:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-03/spring-boot-info-endpoint/</guid>
      <description>In a distributed, fast-paced environment, dev teams often want to find out at what time they deployed the app, what version of the app they deployed, what Git commit was deployed, and more.
Spring Boot Actuator helps us monitor and manage the application. It exposes various endpoints that provide app health, metrics, and other relevant information.
In this article, we will find out how to use Spring Boot Actuator and the Maven/Gradle build plugins to add such information to our projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Applications with Prometheus &#43; Grafana &#43; Spring Boot Actuator</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-02/monitoring-springboot-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 19:01:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-02/monitoring-springboot-applications/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring is often critical in enterprise-level applications. Monitoring can help us prevent failures, predict trends, alert when thresholds are reached, and provide more information to troubleshoot production problems. If we don&amp;rsquo;t know how our program is running, it will take more time to troubleshoot when there is an accident in the online system. If we can monitor in advance, we can prepare early so that we don&amp;rsquo;t get confused after</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Aware of Security Issues Raised by Spring Boot Actuator</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-02/spring-boot-actuator-security-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 14:38:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-02/spring-boot-actuator-security-issues/</guid>
      <description>Recently, we have been particularly disturbed by various security vulnerabilities, and we receive dozens of emails a week from security teams scanning for vulnerabilities. One of these vulnerabilities is easy to overlook, but has a very wide impact and is extremely harmful. You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised when I say its name, it&amp;rsquo;s the Spring Boot Actuator.
Before writing this article, I did a little survey with my friends asking them about their knowledge of the Spring Boot Actuator and the results were amazingly consistent.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
