<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jwt on Spring Cloud</title>
    <link>https://www.springcloud.io/tags/jwt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jwt on Spring Cloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 13:10:13 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.springcloud.io/tags/jwt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to add Json Web Token in Swagger2 or Swagger3</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-02/swagger-jwt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 13:10:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-02/swagger-jwt/</guid>
      <description>1. Preface Swagger 3.0 has been released for some time now, and has been used by more and more projects as a very useful documentation tool. And JWT is also the most commonly used security technology for front-end and back-end separation. So how do you add JWT Token to Swagger 3.0? 2. Adding JWTs in Swagger2 Let&amp;rsquo;s first review how JWT was added in Swagger2. In Swagger2 we declare the</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Security&#39;s new JWT implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-02/spring-security-new-jwt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 12:10:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-02/spring-security-new-jwt/</guid>
      <description>I have used the official spring-security-jwt provided by Spring as an implementation of JWT. This toolkit is no longer maintained. And it is not particularly compatible with the latest Spring Security OAuth2 Client and Spring Authorization Server. So I took two days to re-implement JWT with these two new dependencies.
Nimbus Library The JOSE library nimbus-jose-jwt from Nimbus is used by default in the latest Spring Security. This library is currently one of the most used JOSE class libraries and most of the transformation work has been done around this library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jwt should be present in the cookie</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-02/jwt-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 13:06:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-02/jwt-cookie/</guid>
      <description>I have been using JWT as authentication token for my projects in the last few years. I&amp;rsquo;ve always had a question: where exactly should the server-side issued JWT be stored? Only the browser scenario is discussed here, in which there are three options.
Cookies The server side can send the JWT token to the browser through a cookie, and the browser will automatically bring the JWT token in the cookie header when requesting the server-side interface, and the server side can verify the JWT token in the cookie header to achieve authentication.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
