<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>spring-framework on Spring Cloud</title>
    <link>https://www.springcloud.io/tags/spring-framework/</link>
    <description>Recent content in spring-framework on Spring Cloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 22:39:21 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.springcloud.io/tags/spring-framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spring Framework Data Binding Rules Vulnerability (CVE-2022-22968)</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-framework-data-binding-rules-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 22:39:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-framework-data-binding-rules-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>Overview While investigating the Spring Framework RCE vulnerability CVE-2022-22965 and the suggested workaround, we realized that the disallowedFields configuration setting on WebDataBinder is not intuitive and is not clearly documented. We have fixed that but also decided to be on the safe side and announce a follow-up CVE, in order to ensure application developers are alerted and have a chance to review their configuration.
 CVE-2022-22968: Spring Framework Data Binding Rules Vulnerability  We have released Spring Framework 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 solutions for selective injection when the interface has multiple implementations</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-selective-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 14:48:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-selective-injection/</guid>
      <description>1. Description of the problem In the actual system application development I often encounter such a class of requirements, and I believe that you will often encounter in your work. The same system is deployed in multiple provinces. A business in Beijing is one way of implementation, based on the needs of Beijing users. The same business is implemented in Shanghai in another way, much the same way as in</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadlock problem caused by improper use of ThreadPoolTaskExecutor</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-threadpool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 19:56:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-threadpool/</guid>
      <description>Spring comes with a thread pool is very convenient to use, but in relatively complex concurrent programming scenarios, the use of the scenario still requires careful consideration of the configuration, or you may encounter the pitfalls mentioned in this article. Specific code reference sample project 1. Overview ThredPoolTaskExcutor has 2 core configurations, one is the thread pool size and one is the queue size. The processing flow of ThredPoolTaskExcutor: New</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downgrading to Java 8 can also solve Spring Framework RCE</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-framework-rce-mitigation-alternative/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 21:54:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-framework-rce-mitigation-alternative/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we announced a Spring Framework RCE vulnerability CVE-2022-22965, listing Apache Tomcat as one of several preconditions. The Apache Tomcat team has since released versions 10.0.20 , 9.0.62 , and 8.5.78 all of which close the attack vector on Tomcat&amp;rsquo;s side. While the vulnerability is not in Tomcat itself, in real world situations, it is important to be able to choose among multiple upgrade paths that in turn provides flexibility and layered protection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Framework RCE, Early Announcement</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-03/spring-framework-rce-early-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 19:16:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-03/spring-framework-rce-early-announcement/</guid>
      <description>Updates:
 [15:40 BST] Spring Boot 2.6.6 is available. [14:38 BST] Spring Boot 2.5.12 is available. [14:00 BST] CVE-2022-22965 is published. [13:03 BST] Added section &amp;ldquo;Misconceptions&amp;rdquo;. [12:34 BST] Added section &amp;ldquo;Am I Impacted&amp;rdquo;. [12:11 BST] Fix minor issue in the workaround for adding disallowedFields . [11:59 BST] Spring Framework versions 5.3.18 and 5.2.20 , which address the vulnerability, are now available. The release process for Spring Boot is in progress.  Overview I would like to announce an RCE vulnerability in the Spring Framework that was leaked out ahead of CVE publication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CVE report published for Spring Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-03/cve-report-published-for-spring-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 21:50:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-03/cve-report-published-for-spring-framework/</guid>
      <description>We have released Spring Framework 5.3.17 to address the following CVE report.
 CVE-2022-22950: Spring Expression DoS Vulnerability  Please review the information in the CVE report and upgrade immediately.
Spring Boot users should upgrade to 2.5.11 or 2.6.5.
CVE-2022-22950: Spring Expression DoS Vulnerability   Severity
Medium
  Vendor
Spring by VMware
  Description
In Spring Framework versions 5.3.0 - 5.3.16 and older unsupported versions, it is possible for a user to provide a specially crafted SpEL expression that may cause a denial of service condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 6 And Spring Boot 3</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-02/springframework-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 13:34:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-02/springframework-6/</guid>
      <description>The annual SpringOne conference was held online last September 1-2 due to an epidemic, and Pivotal (the owner of the Spring Project) hosts this conference once a year to meet with thousands of developers, customers and partners from around the world to share technical practices and discuss technology trends. Each conference also reveals the next big step in the Spring Project&amp;rsquo;s evolution. The highlight of this year&amp;rsquo;s conference is definitely Spring Framework 6.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
