<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>spring-cloud-dataflow on Spring Cloud</title>
    <link>https://www.springcloud.io/tags/spring-cloud-dataflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in spring-cloud-dataflow on Spring Cloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 18:48:54 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.springcloud.io/tags/spring-cloud-dataflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Data Flow Shell</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-cloud-dataflow-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 18:48:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-cloud-dataflow-shell/</guid>
      <description>1 Preface In the previous article about Spring Cloud Data Flow, the examples were operated through the UI. The Linux server environment generally uses the command line. The integration on Jenkins does not work with the UI either. The good thing is that the official Data Flow Shell tool is available and can be operated in command line mode, which is very convenient.
The Spring Cloud Data Flow Server provides an operational REST API, so the essence of this Shell tool is still to interact by calling the REST API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Spring Cloud Data Flow, Running in Local Mode</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-cloud-data-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 18:28:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2022-04/spring-cloud-data-flow/</guid>
      <description>1 Preface What is Spring Cloud Data Flow, although it has been around for a while, I think many people don&amp;rsquo;t know about it, because few people use it in their projects. Not much information can be found online. Spring Cloud Data Flow is a microservices-based, specialized framework for streaming and batch data processing. 2 Basic concepts 2.1 Data Processing Modes There are two modes of data processing, Streaming and</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Spring Cloud Data Flow and Confluent Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2021-12/apache-kafka-spring-cloud-data-flow-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 16:02:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.springcloud.io/post/2021-12/apache-kafka-spring-cloud-data-flow-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Data is the currency of competitive advantage in today’s digital age. All organizations struggle with their data due to the sheer variety of data types and ways that it can be shaped, packaged, and evaluated.
Within organizations, teams use different tools, fragmented rule sets, and multiple sources to find value within the data. These operational differences lead to divergent definitions of data and a siloed understanding of the ecosystem.
These challenges have led to the rise of several new technologies, including Apache Kafka® and Spring Cloud Data Flow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
